RESUME FOR AMY METHENY

Contractor Labor Category: Member of the Technical Staff

Level of Security Clearance: Secret

Current/Planned Work Location: Fredericksburg, VA

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:

Ms. Metheny serves as a configuration manager, technical editor, and effort property manager for SimVentions, Inc. She holds the Configuration Management Principles and Implementation Certification for performing CM duties, assists the proposal staff in generating, compiling, and formatting materials in response to RFPs, and supports the technical staff in creating and editing government documents, training materials, and user manuals for various software programs and professional education courses. She has an eye for detail, consistency, and accuracy, and a passion for problem-solving. After working with and around teams of software developers for nearly a decade, and in the final weeks of completing a full-stack web development bootcamp, she is looking to transition to a more technical role.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

<u>SimVentions</u>; 11/2014-Present; 9 years, 6 months; <u>CM/DM/Technical Writer/Editor/PM</u> <u>Analyst/Effort Property Manager</u>

- Exercises CM role utilizing DoDI 5000.02 and ANSI/EIA 649-A standards.
- Coordinates with PM, technical leads, and subcontractors to manage, edit, and deliver all CDRLs for the Track Management contract.
- Manages the reporting, inventory, audit, and record-keeping of all property under the H10 contract (over 400 hundred individual items).
- Participated in Dexter software tool development as part of the Agile team:
 - o Provided testing support for completed stories.
 - Wrote and/or edited software documentation (e.g., user manual, tool tips, installation guide).
 - o Provided guidance on UI/UX design.
 - o Participated in all regular Agile meetings (daily standups, weekly planning meetings, backlog grooming, bi-weekly retrospectives and sprint reviews).
- Supported CM for the TACSIM project, which included:
 - o Reading through and following processes outlined in the established CM Plan
 - o Editing/Updating and delivering project-related documentation (e.g., bi-weekly status reports, SOVT, SSS, SRS, user's manuals, SSDD, IRS)
 - Updating and managing the product backlog across two-week sprints
 - o Ensuring consistency between classified and unclassified backlogs and repositories
 - o Capturing tasks and tracking progress using Microsoft Excel and Jira
 - Utilizing Azure DevOps to manage the project backlog, sprint tasks, testing iterations, and retrospectives
 - o Closing out completed sprints and setting up tasks for new sprints
 - o Merging branches and tagging baselines in both classified and unclassified environments in Git at the conclusion of two-week development sprints

- Working with team members to establish testing plans and procedures
- Auditing current configuration management practices and recommending process improvements
- Utilizing MagicDraw to document software and testing requirements and map/cross-reference those requirements for consistency and accuracy across all project documentation
- Capturing Trouble Reports (TRs) and managing changes through SharePoint workflows
- Transcribing and merging applicable classified scripts to an unclassified server
- Received an introduction to software management tools such as Git and Subversion and their utilization from a CM perspective.
- Managed the hardware procurement process for the TACSIM project, which included:
 - Working with SimV managers and stakeholders to gather technical specification requirements
 - o Conducting market research and gathering quotes to populate the Market Research Workbook
 - Creating entries in JAMIS to initiate the review and approval process for requested hardware purchases
 - Tracking the shipment information and statuses of purchased hardware; coordinating with Facilities and Purchasing to receive, move, and store received equipment
 - Capturing serial numbers and generating DD1149s for hardware to be transferred to government customers
 - o Preparing, measuring, and weighing boxes and printing FedEx labels, as needed, for hardware shipment
 - Recording and updating metadata for purchased hardware in the TACSIM Informedb CM database
- Updated technical documentation to reflect newly instituted hardware procurement processes.
- Participated in the Agile Scrum software development process including attending standups, retrospectives, and planning meetings in order to identify updates, record changes, and solve problems.
- Created CM Plan for PEO Carriers that utilizes the Windchill application for implementation on the Next Gen project.
- Developed, updated, and implemented CM/DM plans, processes, and procedures.
- Worked to develop and document CM processes and charts to govern enterprise-level change management, status accounting/metrics collection, and quality assurance.
- Completed the four-part Configuration Management Principles and Implementation Certification course.
- Performed data management for multiple contracts utilizing multiple document formats through the CM repository, as well as edited those CDRLs for accuracy, consistency, and relevance.
- Utilized SharePoint to manage permissions, maintain a data repository, and ensure a secure document delivery process.
- Developed process documents for generating and updating past performance documents, and for creating training manuals.

• Helped to establish and maintain SimVentions' corporate delivery process that would adhere to new DFARS requirements as well as reduce the burden on the technical staff.

- Edited and formatted the text and graphics for software user manuals, including Program Management and Planning (PMaP), Deployment Extraction Tool for Services (DEXTER), Informedb Enterprise, InformeDDS, Force Level Radar Resource Management (FLRRM) Graphical User Interface (GUI), Enterprise Metacard Builder Resource (EMBR), and the Directed Energy Model and Effects Repository.
- Designed, created, and distributed quarterly training newsletters and individual course announcements via an online marketing tool.
- Designed and formatted one-page Quick Reference Guides (QRGs) for PMaP, Informedb, and the Comment Resolution Macro (CRM).
- Created templates for past performance documentation, training manuals, and professional education course brochures.
- Developed, organized, and formatted training manuals for Informedb Enterprise software and the Train the Trainer course.
- Edited and formatted miscellaneous documents, including the Matrix Organization Manager (MOM) and Prospect Opportunity Planner (POP) process document, Fast Frigate (Mod LCS) Risk Management Plan (RMP), Joint Research and Development (JRAD) design package, sources sought, whitepapers, trip reports, past performances, resumes, meeting minutes, and corporate cutsheets.
- Edited and formatted the following for various proposals (capabilities statements, whitepapers, Small Business Innovative Research [SBIR], Department of Defense Ordnance Technology Consortium [DOTC]):
 - Orals slides in Microsoft PowerPoint
 - Past performances
 - Resumes
 - o Technical volume
 - o Acronym lists
- Managed hundreds of deliverables using the RoadMap web application:
 - o Input identifying information such as submittal dates and title with version number or period of performance.
 - o Attached relevant documents and cover letters associated with deliverables.
 - o Linked objects to their associated program or tool.
- Edited and formatted over three hundred monthly progress reports for a variety of Navy and Marine Corps programs.
 - o Ensured consistency in font, size, and spacing.
 - o Defined acronyms accurately and ensured proper and parallel grammatical usage.
 - o Ensured that line items fell within the period of performance.
- Supported requirements traceability and traceability documentation by performing quality assurance checks and verifying information.
- Provided data management and documentation configuration management and analysis support by creating templates for reports, proposals, and technical documents; sending out reminders to program managers and technical points of contact; and collecting, consolidating, and editing the documents before sending to CM for delivery.
- Created user documentation for a variety of material, including how-to guides and instruction manuals.

• Created tables of contents, figures, and tables, in-text cross-references, and sources cited.

- Edited for organization, content, technical accuracy, and style.
- Followed a document development lifecycle; edited multiple pieces at various levels of development.
- Created an internal style guide and word lists for group use.

Pasternak Media; 09/2013-10/2014; 1 year, 1 month; Post-Production Assistant

- Performed production duties such as loading, setting up, and tearing down equipment; designing sets and lighting schemes; and performing second camera shooting.
- Performed post-production duties such as, but not limited to, the following:
 - o Researched background content for the documentary.
 - o Transcribed footage.
 - o Created motion graphics.
 - o Updated social media related to documentary.
 - o Digitized photographs.
- Cataloged transcripts.
- Compiled research for a commissioned book.
- Designed and distributed an online newsletter.

Non-Relevant Experience: Unemployed (0 yrs., 8 mo.; 12/2012 – 8/2013)

Fredericksburg Fitness; 08/2012-11/2012; 0 years, 3 months; Personal Trainer

 Designed and implemented personalized fitness plans based on clients' goals and capabilities.

Paladin Media Group; 01/2012-07/2012; 0 years, 6 months; Production Assistant

- Assisted in creating 100 short films for the Discovery Education Science Techbook.
- Performed production duties such as loading, setting up, and tearing down equipment.
- Operated the teleprompter.
- Performed post-production duties such as, but not limited to, the following:
 - o Created motion graphics.
 - Labeled and organized media files.
 - o Completed rough cut editing.
 - o Performed content consulting.

EDUCATION/TRAINING:

- Academic:
 - o Certificate; 2023 (pending); Rutgers University; Full-Stack Web Development
 - o M.S.; 2018; West Virginia University; Integrated Marketing Communications
 - o B.A.; 2010; UNC-Wilmington; Film Studies
 - o B.A.; 2010; UNC-Wilmington; Biology
- Non-degree Courses:
 - o Certificate of Completion from Germanna Community College on the Fundamentals of Technical Writing; 21 April 2015; 12 hours

SimVentions, Inc.

 Configuration Management Principles and Implementation Certification; 1 Nov 2018

Resume

- o Software Configuration Management: Strategies, Techniques & Tools Certification; 18 Jul 2019
- Certifications:
 - o Adult and Pediatric First Aid/CPR/AED; 24 May 2015
 - o Certified Personal Trainer; Jun 2012
 - o Certified Massage Therapist; Jun 2011

COMPUTER SKILLS:

- Software development tools and languages:
 - JavaScript
 - o HTML/CSS
 - JQuery
 - o MySQL
 - o MongoDB
 - Express
 - o React
 - o Node
 - o Jira
 - o Git
 - o Azure DevOps
- Microsoft Office (Word, PowerPoint, Excel, Project; Visio)
- SharePoint
- Constant Contact
- Project Management and Planning (PMaP)
- RoadMap/Informedb Enterprise
- Adobe Acrobat
- Adobe After Effects, Photoshop, Premier

AWARDS:

- University Honors (UNCW)
- Departmental Honors (Film Studies UNCW)